So it was my vision from the beginning
that this tool would be an open source
tool. It's really important to understand
that a lot of people don't have the
resources to go out and buy
expensive tools to test their
products for accessibility. And likewise,
they don't have the time to sit
there and do everything manually.
The idea was to take
things that were really
tedious and to try to automate
them in a way that they couldn't be
automated it using current
code inspection techniques,
largely because there wasn't
any data to be manipulated.
And that's what assistive
technology is all about.
It's making sure that people with
disabilities can use the data,
but using their system technology.
So my vision was to find
problems sooner, uh,
to not have a cost associated
with them and to give people
time to focus on accessibility
features that are fun and
innovative and not have to sit there and
hit the tab button 87 times to figure
out if everything was
keyboard accessible or not.
So I'll be talking about my
experience working in this area,
uh, since I did not have a
background of accessibility.
So it has not only added
exposure in my career,
but also helped me to understand the
importance of accessibility since
the automated accessibility testing using
machine learning is a developing area.
And I really enjoyed being in
this challenging environment.
It helped me to come up with my novel
solutions to do something for our
society. And, uh, apart from that,
I got to learn the different phases of
software development that I think it
would definitely help me in the future.
So there's a number of ways that people
can contribute to this project going
forward, thinking of those
methods in terms of t-shirt sizes,
we'll start with extra small
and go up to extra large.
One of the things is we would like it.
If people contributed to the data model,
if you have a good generic data
model that you've built using your
execution,
want to contribute that we can
integrate that in with the products. Um,
also if you find things that we
didn't anticipate, like let's say, uh,
there's a particular
keyboard focus pattern.
That's legitimate that we're not giving
the right results for, for some reason,
reporting those things will allow us
to refine the code in order to produce
better results going forward.
In terms of medium-sized contributions,
we have identified 26 things that
we want to add to this product
above and beyond the five that are
already there and taking one of those on
as either an individual or
as a team of individuals,
maybe a master's degree project or
something like that, be definitely doable.
And then for, uh, the extra large, uh,
people who work for larger companies,
we have had offers of for
contribution of resources.
So we will be getting additional
machine learning resources, for example,
um, and, uh, design reviews
and things like that.
So if you want to participate on a
larger level, that's available as well.
So to contribute to this project,
people can go and look at open
issues in the Gator rappel.
Then they can select issue that interests
them and raise a pull request in the
format, defined in the
contribution dot time defile.
Then moderator will review the changes
and comment if anything needs to be
changed. And, uh, once changes are done,
the contribution will be added to the
project and can be seen in the upcoming
versions.
There area where you can
contribute is in dashboarding.
We will be taking some of the
pieces from the VMware testing as a
service product, and those are going
to be released into open source.
So if you have any experience with
doing accessible test harnesses
or accessible dashboarding
of testing results, uh,
those would be, uh, quite
well received as well.
And if you can't contribute anything,
but you have an idea that you think is
really important, open a ticket and get,
and we'll look at it,
explain why you think it's important
and you talk to your friends about it.
If they can add their comments
to your tickets as well,
to show a widespread
support for your idea.